Maximilian Fuchs

Copenhagen Business School Solbjerg Plads 3 DK-2000 Frederiksberg maximilian-fuchs.github.io +45 50 11 00 49 mfu.fi@cbs.dk

SUMMARY

I am a PhD candidate in financial economics at Copenhagen Business School and former research fellow at the European Central Bank. My interests lie in the nexus of financial markets, climate change, and the broader economy. I enjoy to solve problems leveraging large data and new technologies.

EDUCATION

Visiting Scholar 2023 – 2024

New York University, Stern School of Business

Sponsor: Johannes Stroebel

Ph.D., Financial Economics (expected)

Copenhagen Business School

Advisors: Claus Munk, Jesper Rangvid

M.Sc., Finance and Investments (among top 2% of my class) 2018 – 2020

Copenhagen Business School

Exchange: Shanghai Advanced Institute of Finance, China

B.Sc., Business Administration and Economics (among top 10% of my class) 2013 – 2017

University of Passau

Exchange: Southwestern University of Finance and Economics, China

Professional Experience

European Central Bank

Macroprudential Policy and Financial Stability, Research Fellow

05/2023 - 04/2024

2020 - Today

• Conducted a study on the pricing of climate-related policy risks in Euro area banks' loan portfolios based on large, complex credit register data. A draft is available upon request.

Climate Stress Test Modelling, Trainee

09/2022 - 04/2023

- Contributed to the economy-wide climate stress test by analyzing bank exposure to climate policy risks based on short-term scenarios, including energy and other macroeconomic shocks.
- Analyzed financial and economic developments in the European energy sector during the Ukraine crisis, focusing on impacts on households and firms.

Allianz RE

Climate Risk Pricing

06/2021 - 09/2021

• Developed a model and new financial metrics for pricing physical climate risks in real estate, utilizing internal hazard models for sea level rise and river floods.

Nordea Bank

Market and Counterparty Credit Risk, Student Analyst

11/2018 - 04/2019

- Tested pre-transaction simulations to evaluate sensitivities on various Value at Risk measurement methods.
- Improved data lineage for fixed income and FX securities.

SKILLS

ProgrammingExpert: PYTHON, STATA, I⁴TEX, SQLIntermediate: DASH, HTMLMethodsNatural Language Processing, Panel Econometrics & Causal InferenceDatabasesWRDS, DATASTREAM, ORBIS, CRSP, COMPUSTAT, 13F, BLOOMBERG

Languages Native: German Fluent: English Basic: Mandarin

PhD Coursework Empirical Asset Pricing with Machine Learning, Advanced Asset Pricing,

Advanced Corporate Finance, Advanced Financial Econometrics

RESEARCH

• Carbon VIX: Carbon Price Uncertainty and Decarbonization Investments with Johannes Stroebel and Julian Terstegge
R&R at the Journal of Financial Economics

- Climate Policy Action and the Pricing of Bank Loans with Martina Spaggiari
- Polluters are Short-Lived: Climate Risk and the Timing of Cash Flows

Policy Work:

• The Road to Paris: Stress Testing the Transition Towards a Net-Zero Economy.
with Tina Emambakhsh, Simon Kordel, Charalampos Kouratzoglou, Chiara Lelli, Riccardo Pizzeghello,
Carmelo Salleo, and Martina Spaggiari, ECB Occasional Paper, 2023

Work in Progress:

• Carbon Market Intermediaries

TEACHING & SUPERVISION

Average Evaluation: 4.5/5

Investments, M.Sc. Finance and Investments

2021 – 2022, 2024

Taught exercise classes and TA for Claus Munk

Financial Markets & Instruments, M.Sc. Finance and Strategic Management 2022, 2024 Taught exercise classes and TA for Claus Munk

Capital Market Theory, M.Sc. Applied Economics and Finance 2021, 2024
Taught exercise classes and TA for Claus Munk

Bachelor & Master Theses, Supervision of theses in sustainable finance 2022 – 2024 M.Sc. Advanced Economics and Finance (2x), M.Sc. Applied Economics and Finance (5x), M.Sc. Finance and Investments (7x), B.Sc. International Business (1x)

Presentations

Bank of Italy (scheduled)	Dec 2024
Climate Finance Conference, New York University & Fed New York*	May 2024
Climate Change Center, European Central Bank*	Jun 2023
Copenhagen Business School	Apr 2023
DGMF Seminar, European Central Bank	Jan 2023
World Finance Conference, University of Turin	Aug 2022
Nordic Finance Network Workshop, Stockholm School of Economics	May 2022
PhD Seminar, Copenhagen Business School	Nov 2021

^{*} indicates presentation by co-author

Grants

William Demant Fonden	2023
Augustinus Fonden	2023
Otto Mønsteds Fond	2023
GTN Fonden	2023
COB Rejselegater	2023
European Central Bank	2022
Nordic Finance Network (NFN) Travel Grant	2022

OTHER

$\begin{array}{c} \textbf{Affiliation \&} \\ \textbf{Memberships} \end{array}$	Member of OS-Climate (2021): Open-source climate data and analytics Affiliated with the Danish Pension Research Center (PeRCent)
Volunteering	Speed Up Buddy (since 2020): Mentoring of undergraduate students without

academic background in their families

Help for Ukraine, with Birgitte Weber (since 2018) Collection and distribution of donations for children and families in need in Lviv, Ukraine

REFERENCES

Claus Munk

Professor of Finance Copenhagen Business School cm.fi@cbs.dk

Jesper Rangvid

Professor of Finance Copenhagen Business School $\underline{jr.fi@cbs.dk}$

Johannes Stroebel

Professor of Finance New York University johannes.stroebel@nyu.edu